<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latin American on CDSB</title>
    <link>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/tags/latin-american/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Latin American on CDSB</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018-{year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/tags/latin-american/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CS&amp;S Event Fund award announcement</title>
      <link>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/post/cs_and_s_event_fund_award/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/post/cs_and_s_event_fund_award/</guid>
      <description>We are delighted to announce that Code for Science and Society has selected our application for their first cohort of Event Fund grant recipients as announced on January 25, 2021. The CS&amp;amp;S Event Fund program is made possible through award number GBMF8449 from the Gordon and Betty Moore Foundation (https://doi.org/10.37807/GBMF8449).
Thanks to this support, CDSB along with the Mexican Bioinformatics Network (RMB in Spanish) and the National Node of Bioinformatics at UNAM (NNB-CCG) will be able to carry out a series of short courses throughout 2021 (including one event from December 2020) that will end with the National Bioinformatics Meeting 2021 that will be composed of 6 week-long courses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The impact of CDSB on me</title>
      <link>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/post/the_impact_of_cdsb_on_me/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/post/the_impact_of_cdsb_on_me/</guid>
      <description>By Erick Cuevas Fernández, M. Sc., Bioinformatician. Universidad Nacional Autonoma de Mexico. Universidad Autonoma del Estado de Morelos. Systems Biology and Translational Medicine Laboratory. @ErickCuevasF
In 2018 I heard of a workshop where Martin Morgan was performing in Mexico, at that time I had only a few months learning to use R, and I did not know who Martin Morgan was and had vague notions of Bioconductor. That year I started taking the international bioinformatics workshops.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Latin American communities and organizations: useR!2020 video</title>
      <link>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/post/user_latin_american_community/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/post/user_latin_american_community/</guid>
      <description>This useR!2020 session and video was organized by Laura Acion, Yanina Bellini Saibene, Paola Corrales, and Paloma Rojas Saunero. Leonardo Collado Torres coordinated the blog post submission. This blog post was originally submitted to the R Consortium blog and published there on July 7th 2020.
On June 19th 2020 we filmed a video for useR!2020 showcasing the communities and organizations we are involved in that are for Latin Americans or have Latin American participants.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
