<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>lcollado on CDSB</title>
    <link>/es/authors/lcollado/</link>
    <description>Recent content in lcollado on CDSB</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>es-mx</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018-{year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 04:24:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/es/authors/lcollado/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>CDSBMexico: acuerdense de solicitar becas para ir a BioC2019</title>
      <link>/es/post/cdsbmexico-remember-to-apply-for-bioc2019-travel-scholarships/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 04:24:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/es/post/cdsbmexico-remember-to-apply-for-bioc2019-travel-scholarships/</guid>
      <description>About 10 months ago we announced our plans to start a new community of R/Bioconductor developers in Mexico and Latin America. The National Bioinformatics Node (NNB-UNAM in Spanish) has organized workshops in bioinformatics and R since 2006 and more frequently since 2010. Last year, 2018, there were five simultaneous one week workshops:
 Introduction to R and RStudio
 Exploratory data analysis (EDA) of biological data with R
 EDA of RNA-seq data and differential expression studies</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Gene Regulatory Interaction Formulator For Inquiring Networks</title>
      <link>/es/post/r-gene-regulatory-interaction-formulator-for-inquiring-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 21:45:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/es/post/r-gene-regulatory-interaction-formulator-for-inquiring-networks/</guid>
      <description>This blog post was written by ME Martinez-Sanchez, S Muñoz, M Carrillo, E Azpeitia, D Rosenblueth.
In this blog post we will describe the package rGriffin (Martinez-Sanchez, Muñoz, Carrillo, Azpeitia, et al., 2018) that was one of the projects developed during the TIB2018-BCDW. We hope to continue developing Griffin and rGriffin (Martinez-Sanchez, Muñoz, Carrillo, Azpeitia, et al., 2018). If you have ideas, suggestions or bugs, please contact us via rGriffin GitHub repo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/es/author/lcollado/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/es/author/lcollado/</guid>
      <description>Leonardo usa R diario y ha contribuido paquetes al proyecto de Bioconductor como parte de su trabajo con Andrew Jaffe en LIBD. El está interesado en tecnologías genómicas que generan datos a gran escala como RNA-seq, avances en R y en ayudar a otros a empezar su aventura con R. Leonardo ha estado aprendiendo y enseñando R desde el 2008 y es co-fundador del LIBD rstats club.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>