<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>rstats on CDSB</title>
    <link>/es/categories/rstats/</link>
    <description>Recent content in rstats on CDSB</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>es-mx</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018-{year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 22:50:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/es/categories/rstats/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>El camino de CDSBMexico 2018 a BioC2019</title>
      <link>/es/post/path-from-cdsbmexico-2018-to-bioc2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 22:50:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/es/post/path-from-cdsbmexico-2018-to-bioc2019/</guid>
      <description>Hace un año la Comunidad de Desarrolladores de Software en Bioinformática (CDSB) organizó un taller de una semana diseñado para entrenar a usuarios de R en como crear paquetes de R e idealmente compartirlos vía Bioconductor. El taller en sí fue todo un éxito basado en nuestro resumen del evento. Sin embargo, no queríamos parar ahí. Creamos la CDSB y juntamos fuerzas con los TIB (“Talleres Internacionales de Bioinformática”) de la NNB-UNAM con el objetivo de simular en conjunto un evento anual de BioC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CDSBMexico: acuerdense de solicitar becas para ir a BioC2019</title>
      <link>/es/post/cdsbmexico-remember-to-apply-for-bioc2019-travel-scholarships/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 04:24:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/es/post/cdsbmexico-remember-to-apply-for-bioc2019-travel-scholarships/</guid>
      <description>About 10 months ago we announced our plans to start a new community of R/Bioconductor developers in Mexico and Latin America. The National Bioinformatics Node (NNB-UNAM in Spanish) has organized workshops in bioinformatics and R since 2006 and more frequently since 2010. Last year, 2018, there were five simultaneous one week workshops:
 Introduction to R and RStudio
 Exploratory data analysis (EDA) of biological data with R
 EDA of RNA-seq data and differential expression studies</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Un resumen de CDSB 2018: el inicio de una comunidad</title>
      <link>/es/post/a-recap-of-cdsb-2018-the-start-of-a-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 02:13:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/es/post/a-recap-of-cdsb-2018-the-start-of-a-community/</guid>
      <description>Organizing an event is a lot of work, much more than you plan for it. But harvesting the fruits of a successful event makes the workload worth it.
In July, we kicked off the first Bioconductor Latin American Developers Workshop 2018 (LatAmBioc2018). The main goals of this meeting were to encourage the development of the Bioconductor project in Mexico and to start a community of Mexican bioinformatic software developers – the Community of Bioinformatic Software Developers (CDSB, from its acronym in Spanish).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Gene Regulatory Interaction Formulator For Inquiring Networks</title>
      <link>/es/post/r-gene-regulatory-interaction-formulator-for-inquiring-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 21:45:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/es/post/r-gene-regulatory-interaction-formulator-for-inquiring-networks/</guid>
      <description>This blog post was written by ME Martinez-Sanchez, S Muñoz, M Carrillo, E Azpeitia, D Rosenblueth.
In this blog post we will describe the package rGriffin (Martinez-Sanchez, Muñoz, Carrillo, Azpeitia, et al., 2018) that was one of the projects developed during the TIB2018-BCDW. We hope to continue developing Griffin and rGriffin (Martinez-Sanchez, Muñoz, Carrillo, Azpeitia, et al., 2018). If you have ideas, suggestions or bugs, please contact us via rGriffin GitHub repo.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>