<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Academic</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Academic</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018-{year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 04:24:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>CDSBMexico: remember to apply for BioC2019 travel scholarships</title>
      <link>/post/cdsbmexico-remember-to-apply-for-bioc2019-travel-scholarships/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 04:24:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/cdsbmexico-remember-to-apply-for-bioc2019-travel-scholarships/</guid>
      <description>About 10 months ago we announced our plans to start a new community of R/Bioconductor developers in Mexico and Latin America. The National Bioinformatics Node (NNB-UNAM in Spanish) has organized workshops in bioinformatics and R since 2006 and more frequently since 2010. Last year, 2018, there were five simultaneous one week workshops:
 Introduction to R and RStudio
 Exploratory data analysis (EDA) of biological data with R
 EDA of RNA-seq data and differential expression studies</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A recap of CDSB 2018: the start of a community</title>
      <link>/post/a-recap-of-cdsb-2018-the-start-of-a-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 02:13:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/a-recap-of-cdsb-2018-the-start-of-a-community/</guid>
      <description>Organizing an event is a lot of work, much more than you plan for it. But harvesting the fruits of a successful event makes the workload worth it.
In July, we kicked off the first Bioconductor Latin American Developers Workshop 2018 (LatAmBioc2018). The main goals of this meeting were to encourage the development of the Bioconductor project in Mexico and to start a community of Mexican bioinformatic software developers – the Community of Bioinformatic Software Developers (CDSB, from its acronym in Spanish).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Gene Regulatory Interaction Formulator For Inquiring Networks</title>
      <link>/post/r-gene-regulatory-interaction-formulator-for-inquiring-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 21:45:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/r-gene-regulatory-interaction-formulator-for-inquiring-networks/</guid>
      <description>_This blog post was contributed by: ME Martinez-Sanchez, S Muñoz, M Carrillo, E Azpeitia, D Rosenblueth_
In this blog post we will describe the package rGriffin that was one of the projects developed during the TIB2018-BCDW. We hope to continue developing Griffin and rGriffin. If you have ideas, suggestions or bugs, please contact us at Github.
The problem Boolean networks allow us to give a mechanistic explanation to how cell types emerge from regulatory networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Latin American R/BioConductor Developers Workshop 2018</title>
      <link>/post/r-bioconductor-developers-workshop-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 12:40:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/r-bioconductor-developers-workshop-2018/</guid>
      <description>Comunidad de Desarrolladores de Software en Bioinformática  Conference webpage: http://www.comunidadbioinfo.org/r-bioconductor-developers-workshop-2018/
 Level: intermediate - advanced
 Language: english
 When: July 30 - August 3, 2018
 Where: Auditorium of the Center for Genomic Sciences, Cuernavaca, Mexico
 Twitter: #CDSBMexico
 Facebook: @CDSBMexico
 GitHub: https://github.com/ComunidadBioInfo/R-BioConductor-Developers-Workshop-2018
   Regístrate
Pre-requisitos Requisitos de conocimientos previos
 Los participantes deberán tener conocimientos básicos del lenguaje de programación R: asignación de variables, lectura de archivos: read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talleres Internacionales de Bioinformática 2018</title>
      <link>/post/talleres-internacionales-de-bioinformatica-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 18:12:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/talleres-internacionales-de-bioinformatica-2018/</guid>
      <description>El Nodo Nacional de Bioinformática (NNB-UNAM) y la Comunidad de Desarrolladores de Software en Bioinformática (CDSB) te invitan a
TIB2018: R para todos &amp;amp; Latin American R/Bioconductor Developers Workshop
Centro de Ciencias Genómicas-UNAM (CCG-UNAM), en Cuernavaca Morelos, México. 30 de Julio al 3 de Agosto de 2018
Este año, hemos decidido unir esfuerzos para impulsar el desarrollo de habilidades en el lenguaje de programación R, bajo el slogan “Aprende R y hagamos comunidad”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>La Bioinformática, una disciplina en auge en el mundo</title>
      <link>/post/la-bioinformatica-una-disciplina-en-auge-en-el-mundo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 20:49:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/la-bioinformatica-una-disciplina-en-auge-en-el-mundo/</guid>
      <description>La Bioinformática es un área interdisciplinaria en la que convergen las tecnologías de la información y las comunicaciones con las ciencias de la vida, donde los recursos computacionales y humanos asisten al análisis de cantidades enormes de datos biológicos, para extraer de ellos información valiosa y obtener resultados con impactos beneficiosos en la salud humana o animal (González Hernández D., 2007).
Desde la segunda mitad del siglo XX, la biología ha tenido una relación creciente con las ciencias de la información.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>