<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on CDSB</title>
    <link>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on CDSB</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018-{year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Workshops CDSB 2021: RStudio workflows and scRNA-seq with Bioconductor</title>
      <link>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/post/cdsb-2021-workshops/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/post/cdsb-2021-workshops/</guid>
      <description>We are delighted to announce that CDSB, along with the Mexican Bioinformatics Network (RMB in Spanish) and the National Node of Bioinformatics at UNAM (NNB-CCG), is organizing two week-long workshops this summer as part of the National Bioinformatics Meeting Mexico 2021. These are:
 Workflows with RStudio and creating shiny apps Analysis of scRNA-seq data with Bioconductor  These workshops will be held online on August 9 to 13, 2021 and you can register here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CS&amp;S Event Fund award announcement</title>
      <link>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/post/cs_and_s_event_fund_award/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/post/cs_and_s_event_fund_award/</guid>
      <description>We are delighted to announce that Code for Science and Society has selected our application for their first cohort of Event Fund grant recipients as announced on January 25, 2021. The CS&amp;amp;S Event Fund program is made possible through award number GBMF8449 from the Gordon and Betty Moore Foundation (https://doi.org/10.37807/GBMF8449).
Thanks to this support, CDSB along with the Mexican Bioinformatics Network (RMB in Spanish) and the National Node of Bioinformatics at UNAM (NNB-CCG) will be able to carry out a series of short courses throughout 2021 (including one event from December 2020) that will end with the National Bioinformatics Meeting 2021 that will be composed of 6 week-long courses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The impact of CDSB on me</title>
      <link>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/post/the_impact_of_cdsb_on_me/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/post/the_impact_of_cdsb_on_me/</guid>
      <description>By Erick Cuevas Fernández, M. Sc., Bioinformatician. Universidad Nacional Autonoma de Mexico. Universidad Autonoma del Estado de Morelos. Systems Biology and Translational Medicine Laboratory. @ErickCuevasF
In 2018 I heard of a workshop where Martin Morgan was performing in Mexico, at that time I had only a few months learning to use R, and I did not know who Martin Morgan was and had vague notions of Bioconductor. That year I started taking the international bioinformatics workshops.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Latin American communities and organizations: useR!2020 video</title>
      <link>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/post/user_latin_american_community/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/post/user_latin_american_community/</guid>
      <description>This useR!2020 session and video was organized by Laura Acion, Yanina Bellini Saibene, Paola Corrales, and Paloma Rojas Saunero. Leonardo Collado Torres coordinated the blog post submission. This blog post was originally submitted to the R Consortium blog and published there on July 7th 2020.
On June 19th 2020 we filmed a video for useR!2020 showcasing the communities and organizations we are involved in that are for Latin Americans or have Latin American participants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CDSB: the story of a diversity and outreach hotspot in Mexico that hopes to empower local R developers</title>
      <link>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/post/csdb-story-of-a-diversity-and-outreach-hotspot-in-mexico/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/post/csdb-story-of-a-diversity-and-outreach-hotspot-in-mexico/</guid>
      <description>This blog post was submitted to the R Consortium blog where it was published on 03/18/2020.
I have been attending R conferences since 2008, and while I’ve seen the R community grow rapidly, I generally don’t encounter as many Latin Americans (LatAm) among communities of R developers. Traditionally, a lab lead investigator invested in R or Bioconductor would teach their trainees and students these skills, becoming a local R hotspot. However, that scenario is uncommon in Mexico for several reasons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BioC2019 Code of Conduct violation response</title>
      <link>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/post/bioc2019-code-of-conduct-violation-response/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/post/bioc2019-code-of-conduct-violation-response/</guid>
      <description>For the English version of this statement, please go to the BioC2019 Code of Conduct website. At CDSB&amp;rsquo;s website you can find the translated Spanish version of this statement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CDSB Workshop 2020: Building workflows with RStudio and Bioconductor for single cell RNA-seq analysis</title>
      <link>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/post/cdsb2020-building-workflows-with-rstudio-and-scrnaseq-with-bioconductor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/post/cdsb2020-building-workflows-with-rstudio-and-scrnaseq-with-bioconductor/</guid>
      <description>This workshop is part of the Mexican Bioinformatics Encounter (EBM in Spanish) 2020 organized by CDSB with:
   TIB2020 RMB NNB CCG-UNAM            Community of Bioinformatics Software Developers (CDSB)   Workshop webpage
  Level: intermediate - advanced
  Language: Spanish
  When: August 3 - August 7, 2020 (9 am to 5:30 pm, Friday until 2:30 pm)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Bioconductor users to developers: our first community submission</title>
      <link>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/post/from-bioconductor-users-to-developers-our-first-community-submission/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/post/from-bioconductor-users-to-developers-our-first-community-submission/</guid>
      <description>A couple years ago we started the Community of Bioinformatics Software Developers (CDSB in Spanish) as because we were concerned with the very low representation of Latin Americans in the Bioconductor community, and the R community in general. For the full story check this this blog post.
 Since we started CDSB, part of our goal been to help Bioconductor users transition into developers. To achieve this, we organized one week long courses in Mexico at low cost during the summers of 2018 and 2019 in partnership with the TIBs leadership (NNB-UNAM) and RMB.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CDSB Workshop 2019: How to Build and Create Tidy Tools</title>
      <link>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/post/building-tidy-tools-cdsb-runconf-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/post/building-tidy-tools-cdsb-runconf-2019/</guid>
      <description>Community of Bioinformatics Software Developers   Workshop webpage: https://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/post/building-tidy-tools-CDSB-runconf-2019/
  Level: intermediate - advanced
  Language: Spanish^[If you speak English but not Spanish please let us know so we can plan accordingly.]
  When: July 29 - August 2, 2019
  Where: Auditorium of the Center for Genomic Sciences, Cuernavaca, Mexico
  Twitter: #CDSBMexico
  Facebook: @CDSBMexico
  GitHub: https://github.com/ComunidadBioInfo/tidy-tools-CDSB-runconf-2019
  Registration</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bioinformatics Mexican Meeting 2019</title>
      <link>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/post/talleres-internacionales-de-bioinformatica-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/post/talleres-internacionales-de-bioinformatica-2019/</guid>
      <description>The National Node of Bioinformatics (NNB-UNAM), the Mexican Bioinformatics Network (RMB) and the Community of Bioinformatics Software Developers (CDSB) invite you to Bioinformatics Mexican Meeting 2019 composed by
International Bioinformatics Workshops (TIB2019) &amp;amp;
CDSB Workshop: How To Build and Create Tidy Tools UNAM Center for Genomic Sciences (CCG-UNAM) in Cuernavaca Morelos, Mexico. From July 29 to August 9, 2019
The workshops are organized by:
 NNB-UNAM, Mexican node EMBNet (European Molecular Biology network) Community of Bioinformatics Software Developers (CDSB) Mexican Bioinformatics Network (RMB)  thanks to the:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The path from CDSBMexico 2018 to BioC2019</title>
      <link>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/post/path-from-cdsbmexico-2018-to-bioc2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 22:50:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/post/path-from-cdsbmexico-2018-to-bioc2019/</guid>
      <description>Last year the Community of Bioinformatics Software Developers (CDSB in Spanish) organized a one week workshop designed to train R users how to write R packages and ideally contribute them to Bioconductor. The workshop itself was a success as described in our summary post about the event. However, we didn’t want to stop there. We formed CDSB and teamed up with TIB (“Talleres Internacionales de Bioinformática”) from NNB-UNAM with the goal of simulating the BioC yearly meeting where attendees can learn R, mature as R users and become R developers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CDSBMexico: remember to apply for BioC2019 travel scholarships</title>
      <link>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/post/cdsbmexico-remember-to-apply-for-bioc2019-travel-scholarships/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 04:24:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/post/cdsbmexico-remember-to-apply-for-bioc2019-travel-scholarships/</guid>
      <description>About 10 months ago we announced our plans to start a new community of R/Bioconductor developers in Mexico and Latin America. The National Bioinformatics Node (NNB-UNAM in Spanish) has organized workshops in bioinformatics and R since 2006 and more frequently since 2010. Last year, 2018, there were five simultaneous one week workshops:
  Introduction to R and RStudio
  Exploratory data analysis (EDA) of biological data with R</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A recap of CDSB 2018: the start of a community</title>
      <link>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/post/a-recap-of-cdsb-2018-the-start-of-a-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 02:13:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/post/a-recap-of-cdsb-2018-the-start-of-a-community/</guid>
      <description>Organizing an event is a lot of work, much more than you plan for it. But harvesting the fruits of a successful event makes the workload worth it.
In July, we kicked off the first Bioconductor Latin American Developers Workshop 2018 (LatAmBioc2018). The main goals of this meeting were to encourage the development of the Bioconductor project in Mexico and to start a community of Mexican bioinformatic software developers – the Community of Bioinformatic Software Developers (CDSB, from its acronym in Spanish).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Gene Regulatory Interaction Formulator For Inquiring Networks</title>
      <link>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/post/r-gene-regulatory-interaction-formulator-for-inquiring-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 21:45:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/post/r-gene-regulatory-interaction-formulator-for-inquiring-networks/</guid>
      <description>This blog post was written by ME Martinez-Sanchez, S Muñoz, M Carrillo, E Azpeitia, D Rosenblueth.
In this blog post we will describe the package rGriffin (Martinez-Sanchez, Muñoz, Carrillo, Azpeitia, et al., 2018) that was one of the projects developed during the TIB2018-BCDW. We hope to continue developing Griffin and rGriffin (Martinez-Sanchez, Muñoz, Carrillo, Azpeitia, et al., 2018). If you have ideas, suggestions or bugs, please contact us via rGriffin GitHub repo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Latin American R/BioConductor Developers Workshop 2018</title>
      <link>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/post/r-bioconductor-developers-workshop-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 12:40:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/post/r-bioconductor-developers-workshop-2018/</guid>
      <description>Community of Bioinformatics Software Developers   Workshop webpage: https://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/post/r-bioconductor-developers-workshop-2018/
  Level: intermediate - advanced
  Language: english
  When: July 30 - August 3, 2018
  Where: Auditorium of the Center for Genomic Sciences, Cuernavaca, Mexico
  Twitter: #CDSBMexico
  Facebook: @CDSBMexico
  GitHub: https://github.com/ComunidadBioInfo/R-BioConductor-Developers-Workshop-2018
  Register
  Requirements Requirements prior knowledge
 Participants should have basic knowledge of programming language R: variable assignment, reading files: read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 International Workshop on Bioinformatics</title>
      <link>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/post/talleres-internacionales-de-bioinformatica-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 18:12:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/post/talleres-internacionales-de-bioinformatica-2018/</guid>
      <description>The National Node of Bioinformatics (NNB-UNAM) and the Community of Bioinformatics Software Developers (CDSB) invite you to
TIB2018: R para todos &amp;amp; Latin American R/Bioconductor Developers Workshop UNAM Center for Genomic Sciences (CCG-UNAM) in Cuernavaca Morelos, Mexico. From July 30 to August 3, 2018
This year, we decided to join efforts to promote the development of skills in the programming language R, under the slogan &amp;ldquo;Learn R and do community&amp;rdquo; .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bioinformatics, a field on the rise in the world</title>
      <link>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/post/la-bioinformatica-una-disciplina-en-auge-en-el-mundo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 20:49:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/post/la-bioinformatica-una-disciplina-en-auge-en-el-mundo/</guid>
      <description>La Bioinformática es un área interdisciplinaria en la que convergen las tecnologías de la información y las comunicaciones con las ciencias de la vida, donde los recursos computacionales y humanos asisten al análisis de cantidades enormes de datos biológicos, para extraer de ellos información valiosa y obtener resultados con impactos beneficiosos en la salud humana o animal (González Hernández D**., 2007).**
Desde la segunda mitad del siglo XX, la biología ha tenido una relación creciente con las ciencias de la información.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
