<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>lcollado on CDSB</title>
    <link>/authors/lcollado/</link>
    <description>Recent content in lcollado on CDSB</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018-{year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 22:50:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/authors/lcollado/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The path from CDSBMexico 2018 to BioC2019</title>
      <link>/post/path-from-cdsbmexico-2018-to-bioc2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 22:50:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/path-from-cdsbmexico-2018-to-bioc2019/</guid>
      <description>Last year the Community of Bioinformatics Software Developers (CDSB in Spanish) organized a one week workshop designed to train R users how to write R packages and ideally contribute them to Bioconductor. The workshop itself was a success as described in our summary post about the event. However, we didn’t want to stop there. We formed CDSB and teamed up with TIB (“Talleres Internacionales de Bioinformática”) from NNB-UNAM with the goal of simulating the BioC yearly meeting where attendees can learn R, mature as R users and become R developers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CDSBMexico: remember to apply for BioC2019 travel scholarships</title>
      <link>/post/cdsbmexico-remember-to-apply-for-bioc2019-travel-scholarships/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 04:24:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/cdsbmexico-remember-to-apply-for-bioc2019-travel-scholarships/</guid>
      <description>About 10 months ago we announced our plans to start a new community of R/Bioconductor developers in Mexico and Latin America. The National Bioinformatics Node (NNB-UNAM in Spanish) has organized workshops in bioinformatics and R since 2006 and more frequently since 2010. Last year, 2018, there were five simultaneous one week workshops:
 Introduction to R and RStudio
 Exploratory data analysis (EDA) of biological data with R
 EDA of RNA-seq data and differential expression studies</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Gene Regulatory Interaction Formulator For Inquiring Networks</title>
      <link>/post/r-gene-regulatory-interaction-formulator-for-inquiring-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 21:45:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/r-gene-regulatory-interaction-formulator-for-inquiring-networks/</guid>
      <description>This blog post was written by ME Martinez-Sanchez, S Muñoz, M Carrillo, E Azpeitia, D Rosenblueth.
In this blog post we will describe the package rGriffin (Martinez-Sanchez, Muñoz, Carrillo, Azpeitia, et al., 2018) that was one of the projects developed during the TIB2018-BCDW. We hope to continue developing Griffin and rGriffin (Martinez-Sanchez, Muñoz, Carrillo, Azpeitia, et al., 2018). If you have ideas, suggestions or bugs, please contact us via rGriffin GitHub repo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/author/lcollado/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/author/lcollado/</guid>
      <description>Leonardo uses R daily and contributes packages to the Bioconductor project as part of his work with Andrew Jaffe at LIBD. He is interested in high-throughput genomics assays such as RNA-seq, developments in R and helping others get started in their R journey. Leonardo has been learning and teaching R since 2008 and is a co-founder of the LIBD rstats club.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>