<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Authors on CDSB</title>
    <link>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Authors on CDSB</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018-{year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/admin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/admin/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the Community of Bioinformatics Software Developers (CDSB in Spanish)!
We are a group interested in helping members of Latin American countries acquire the necessary skills to contribute to open source software development. R is now used by many industries and has been a long time favorite in academia. As R users grow more familiar with the language, they typically end up writing their own functions and sharing them with others via packages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/lcollado/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/lcollado/</guid>
      <description>Leonardo uses R daily and contributes R packages to the Bioconductor project as part of his work at LIBD. He is interested in high-throughput genomics assays such as RNA-seq, developments in R and helping others get started in their R journey. Leonardo has been learning and teaching R since 2008 and is a co-founder of the LIBD rstats club.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/erickcufe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/erickcufe/</guid>
      <description>I am a Biological Data Scientist. I am also a Scientist and Entrepreneur in training. I have a Masters degree in Biochemical Sciences at UNAM and I am currently a Ph.D. student at UNAM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/areyes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 02:13:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/areyes/</guid>
      <description>I am a Data Scientist for Early Drug Development at Novartis Institute for BioMedical Research. I develop computational strategies to translate large amounts of data into biological knowledge. I implement my analyses in documented workflows, software packages and graphic interphases. I am a contributor of software to the Bioconductor project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/delfinog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 20:49:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/delfinog/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/aescalante/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/aescalante/</guid>
      <description>Con formación como Actuario por la Benemérita Universidad Autónoma de Puebla (BUAP), inicié mi camino profesional como Data Scientist hace 4 años. Actualmente, trabajo como Analytics Developer en el equipo global de Kantar, en donde hago desarrollo de software con R.
Disfruto aplicar conocimientos en desarrollo y ciencia de datos para crear y mantener paquetes para facilitar los procesos de análisis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/alabasti/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/alabasti/</guid>
      <description>Aurora Labastida Martínez estudió la Licenciatura en Investigación Biomédica Básica y la Maestría en Ciencias Bioquímicas en la UNAM. Se dedica al análisis de datos de secuenciación masiva de ADN y ha formado parte de distintos equipos de de biólogos y programadores en instituciones públicas y privadas.
Actualmente dirige el servicio de análisis de datos OMICs Analysis, que brinda sus servicios a científicos y empresas en proyectos de metagenómica y transcriptómica.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/amedina/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/amedina/</guid>
      <description>Alejandra obtained her Ph.D. in 2012 from the Biomedical Sciences Program at the National University of Mexico (UNAM). Since her Ph.D., she has been focused on developing bioinformatic tools, and strategies to study gene regulatory mechanisms, most of the developed tools are now part of the Regulatory Sequence and Analysis Tools suite (RSAT, http://rsat.eu/). Currently, using computational approaches, her research will incorporate functional genomics data into Genome Wide Association Studies (GWAS), aiming to identify variants that lead to misregulation of gene expression.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/anabva/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/anabva/</guid>
      <description>Ana B learned to program in R, currently, she uses it daily, and has given workshops, classes, and consultancies at all levels. She is co-founder of Rladies-Querétaro, uses R in her transcriptomic analysis, and has created a package in R and several web applications. She also programs in Python for her analyses, uses Django for web applications, and has experience in relational databases such as MySQL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/aponce/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/aponce/</guid>
      <description>Hi !!! I Studied Food Technology at UIA and my masters and PhD in Biotechnology and Bioengineering at CINVESTAV. I&amp;rsquo;ve have had several years in postdocs and jobs at many Institutions (ECOSUR, UNSIJ, INIFAP, CONABIO, UAM-X). I&amp;rsquo;m interested in numerical ecology, data visualization and agrobiodiversity. Finally, I practice touring bike and admire Thomas Bernhard, WG Sebald and Glenn Gould.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/bcarvalho/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/bcarvalho/</guid>
      <description>Statistician (BS, M.Sc.), biostatistician (Ph.D.) Instructor: Statistics - Regression Models; Database designer and developer: MySQL, PHP; Teacher Assistant: Biocomputing, Statistical Computing and Statistical Methods in Public Health; Developer: BioConductor - oligo, makePlatformDesign, crlmm, pdInfoBuilder. Specialties: High-throughput genotyping, microarray preprocessing, statistical modeling, gene-expression analyzes, genetic epidemiology, statistical computing, programming (R, C / C ++, MATLAB)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/carbarjon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/carbarjon/</guid>
      <description>Author of regutools that was submitted to Bioconductor.
Description from here:
 I&amp;rsquo;m (also) a graduate of the Undergraduate Program on Genomic Sciences from the National Autonomous University of Mexico (UNAM). My current project in MorenoLab involves the analysis of identity-by-descent genomic segments to determine the population structure of Mexico and their implications in biomedical traits using the data from the Mexican BioBank. I am also involved in other projects as the Oceanian Genome Variation Project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/citlaliga/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/citlaliga/</guid>
      <description>I studied genomic sciences at UNAM. I&amp;rsquo;d worked on various projects focused on population genetics and evolution. Some of my current interests are: philosophy, programming (R, python and trying arduino), science communication ( Más ciencia por México ), I really love teaching and learning from others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/emarquezz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/emarquezz/</guid>
      <description>Elisa integrates multiple omics and phenotypic data with genome-scale metabolic modeling for rational strain design and bioprocess optimization project as part of his work at CCG with Utrilla Lab. She is interested in the integration of different types of data such as RNA-seq, proteomics, Ribo-seq and fitness information, with metabolism and expression models built with thepython module COBRAme. Her objective is to make a quantitative comparison between genome and proteome reduction strategies for redirecting cellular resources to synthetic functions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/hsalgado/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/hsalgado/</guid>
      <description>Bioinformatician. I am interested in disseminating and supporting the teaching of bioinformatics in Mexico and LA (@swcarpentry, @ComunidadBioInfo and NNB)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/jemilianosf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/jemilianosf/</guid>
      <description>Author of regutools that was submitted to Bioconductor.
regrnalab member.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/josschavezf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/josschavezf/</guid>
      <description>During my PhD project, in the Computational Genomics Laboratory at IBT-UNAM, I focused on the study of bacterial transcriptional regulators through evolution. Additionally, I gained experience in writing R/Bioconductor packages and teaching R.
Currently, I&amp;rsquo;m a Postdoctoral Fellow in the Department of Personalized Medicine of the Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai, in New York City. My main interest is bioinformatics and the development of open source software for the analysis of single cell and spatial transcriptomics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/lgomez/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/lgomez/</guid>
      <description>Laura enjoys teaching bioinformatic courses. Her research interest are focused on genomic variation and its link with human diseases. She has wide experience with R, python and other programming languages oriented to solve biological questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/mirnavrl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/mirnavrl/</guid>
      <description>Mirna Vázquez Rosas Landa estudió su doctorado en el Instituto de Ecología de la UNAM. En su tesis analizó los genomas de las bacterias que viven en las pozas de Cuatro Ciénegas buscando señales de adaptación al ambiente. Posteriormente realizó una estancia postdoctoral en el Instituto de Ecología en Xalapa, Veracruz, donde se dedicó a buscar estrategias amigables con el ambiente para el control de plagas utilizando diversas ciencias ómicas como herramienta.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/mramos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/mramos/</guid>
      <description>Marcel has written or contributed to over 9 packages in Bioconductor and CRAN. He is interested in Bioconductor data classes and representations for the analysis of multi-omic and multi-modal data. He is the developer of the MultiAssayExperiment package, currently in the top 10% most downloaded in Bioconductor. Marcel also has teaching appointments at the CUNY School of Public Health on introductory topics in Biostatistics, R, and SAS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/mteresa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/mteresa/</guid>
      <description>I am a data analyst with experience in ecology and marketing, I currently work in Kantar where I do software development with R.
I also enjoy teaching, I teach statistic courses to master students in Data Science and to bachelors in Mathematics and Actuarial Sciences at ITAM. Lastly, I love R, I am co-organizer of R-Ladies CDMX and I regularly give short courses in R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/mtmorgan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/mtmorgan/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Morgan spent 10 years as an Assistant Professor and Associate then at Washington State University, before joining the Fred Hutchinson Cancer Research Center in 2005. At the Hutch, Dr. Morgan worked on the Bioconductor project for the analysis and comprehension of high-throughput genomic data; which he has led since 2008. Dr. Morgan recently moved to Roswell Park in Buffalo Comprehensive Cancer Center, NY, where the Bioconductor project is now based.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/robamezquita/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/robamezquita/</guid>
      <description>Robert Amezquita is a Postdoctoral Fellow in the Immunotherapy Integrated Research Center (IIRC) at Fred Hutch under the mentorship of Raphael Gottardo. His current research focuses on utilizing computational approaches leveraging transcriptional and epigenomic profiling at single-cell resolution to understand how novel anti-cancer therapeutics - ranging from small molecule therapies to biologics such as CAR-T cells - affect immune response dynamics. Extending from his graduate work at Yale’s Dept. of Immunobiology, Robert’s research aims to better understand the process of immune cell differentiation under the duress of cancer as a means to inform future immunotherapies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/roramirezf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/roramirezf/</guid>
      <description>Ricardo uses statistics to analyze multiomics data at different scales. His research interests are focused in the study of tissue architecture and its disruption during disease. He uses single cell data and spatial technologies to achieve this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/sfernandez/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/sfernandez/</guid>
      <description>Selene Fernandez is a bioinformatician / genomic data scientist studying the evolution of gene regulatory mechanisms underlying the phenotypic diversity and differentiation in multicellular eukaryotes cell. She is particularly interested in the evolution of regulatory roles of non-coding RNAs.
In addition to her academic roles, she participates in initiatives that link scientists and the general public (such as Más Ciencia por Mexico, Clubes de Ciencia Mexico), programs to introduce researchers to computing (Software/Data Carpentry) as well as mentoring programs (Ekpapalek).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/yalbibalderas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/authors/yalbibalderas/</guid>
      <description>Yalbi Balderas is interested in studying respiratory diseases through high-throughput assays such as microarrays, bulk or single cell RNA-seq. She teaches several courses of statistics and bioinformatics at UNAM.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
