<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>admin on CDSB</title>
    <link>/authors/admin/</link>
    <description>Recent content in admin on CDSB</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018-{year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 13:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/authors/admin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>CDSB Workshop 2019: How to Build and Create Tidy Tools</title>
      <link>/post/building-tidy-tools-cdsb-runconf-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/building-tidy-tools-cdsb-runconf-2019/</guid>
      <description>Community of Bioinformatics Software Developers  Workshop webpage: https://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/post/building-tidy-tools-CDSB-runconf-2019/
 Level: intermediate - advanced
 Language: Spanish1
 When: July 29 - August 2, 2019
 Where: Auditorium of the Center for Genomic Sciences, Cuernavaca, Mexico
 Twitter: #CDSBMexico
 Facebook: @CDSBMexico
 GitHub: https://github.com/ComunidadBioInfo/tidy-tools-CDSB-runconf-2019
 Registration
  Requirements Requirements prior knowledge
 Participants should have basic to intermediate knowledge of the R programming language: variable assignment, reading files: read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bioinformatics Mexican Meeting 2019</title>
      <link>/post/talleres-internacionales-de-bioinformatica-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/talleres-internacionales-de-bioinformatica-2019/</guid>
      <description>The National Node of Bioinformatics (NNB-UNAM), the Mexican Bioinformatics Network (RMB) and the Community of Bioinformatics Software Developers (CDSB) invite you to Bioinformatics Mexican Meeting 2019 composed by
International Bioinformatics Workshops (TIB2019) &amp;amp;
CDSB Workshop: How To Build and Create Tidy Tools UNAM Center for Genomic Sciences (CCG-UNAM) in Cuernavaca Morelos, Mexico. From July 29 to August 9, 2019
The workshops are organized by:
 NNB-UNAM, Mexican node EMBNet (European Molecular Biology network)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code of conduct</title>
      <link>/codigo-de-conducta/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 15:09:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/codigo-de-conducta/</guid>
      <description>The Community of Software Developers in Bioinformatics (CDSB) is committed to providing a welcoming and free experience harassment for all, regardless of gender, gender identity and expression, age, sexual orientation, disability, physical appearance, body size, race , ethnicity, religion (or lack thereof) or technology options. We do not tolerate harassment of participants of the conference in any way. Language and sexual images are not suitable for any place of the conference, including lectures, workshops, parties, Twitter and other online media.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Latin American R/BioConductor Developers Workshop 2018</title>
      <link>/post/r-bioconductor-developers-workshop-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 12:40:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/r-bioconductor-developers-workshop-2018/</guid>
      <description>Community of Bioinformatics Software Developers  Workshop webpage: https://comunidadbioinfo.github.io/post/r-bioconductor-developers-workshop-2018/
 Level: intermediate - advanced
 Language: english
 When: July 30 - August 3, 2018
 Where: Auditorium of the Center for Genomic Sciences, Cuernavaca, Mexico
 Twitter: #CDSBMexico
 Facebook: @CDSBMexico
 GitHub: https://github.com/ComunidadBioInfo/R-BioConductor-Developers-Workshop-2018
 Register
  Requirements Requirements prior knowledge
 Participants should have basic knowledge of programming language R: variable assignment, reading files: read.csv, read.delim, read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 International Workshop on Bioinformatics</title>
      <link>/post/talleres-internacionales-de-bioinformatica-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 18:12:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/talleres-internacionales-de-bioinformatica-2018/</guid>
      <description>The National Node of Bioinformatics (NNB-UNAM) and the Community of Bioinformatics Software Developers (CDSB) invite you to
TIB2018: R para todos &amp;amp; Latin American R/Bioconductor Developers Workshop UNAM Center for Genomic Sciences (CCG-UNAM) in Cuernavaca Morelos, Mexico. From July 30 to August 3, 2018
This year, we decided to join efforts to promote the development of skills in the programming language R, under the slogan &amp;ldquo;Learn R and do community&amp;rdquo; .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aviso de Privacidad para la Protección de Datos Personales</title>
      <link>/aviso-de-privacidad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 17:23:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/aviso-de-privacidad/</guid>
      <description>See version in Spanish. This privacy notice is for those of you in Mexico.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/author/admin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/author/admin/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the Community of Bioinformatics Software Developers (CDSB in Spanish)!
We are a group interested in helping members of Latin American countries acquire the necessary skills to contribute to open source software development. R is now used by many industries and has been a long time favorite in academia. As R users grow more familiar with the language, they typically end up writing their own functions and sharing them with others via packages.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>